[gentle music]
♪ ♪
All right, Julius,
you need to stay here
and rest until
you've finished healing
no matter what!
You heard her.
Yes, of course.
I've already caused
more than enough trouble
for you and Ms. Emelia.
And after all that's
transpired until now,
I wouldn't dare
shamelessly disobey.
I shall be obedient.
Just so you know,
an "understood"
would have sufficed, buddy.
Exactly.
You really don't have
to worry about us.
All we're saying is that
you need to rest properly.
Feel free to trouble us
as much as you want.
'Cause friends help each other.
So, Patrashce, would
you look after Julius?
If anything odd happens
again, call us right away,
and we'll come
as fast as we can.
[murmurs]
See, look.
Even she's saying,
(GRAVELY VOICE)
you better stay in line
'cause I'm not letting you
get away from me next time.
Got it?
- Strangely enough,
I think it really did sound
like those were the words
she was trying to speak.
If I want to be more accurate,
she's a lady,
(HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
so she'd sound more like this.
[chuckles]
♪ ♪
Yes, I will behave myself
and focus on my recovery.
And after all,
how could I refuse
when afforded the luxury of
resting among maidens as lovely
as these?
[chuckles] Feeling more
like yourself again, I see.
Will Julius be
all right, I suppose?
No need to worry.
Seems he's past
the worst of it already.
After what
Gluttony did to him,
I never would have
thought he'd act so
recklessly in that situation.
Well, I mean, yeah,
I agree with you there.
But what he did was basically
the equivalent of a man
getting a case of the measles.
That was us getting lucky.
It could have meant
failure for all of us
because he acted on his own.
If that had happened,
I'm not sure the examiner
on the second floor
would have let us
leave that place unscathed.
Us, including
the sage imposter.
Who, me?
Whoa!
That's super mean to say.
For starters, I never even
claimed to be a dang sage.
The only name I have is
the one my master gave me,
and that is Shaula, OK?
And I only have eyes for him.
Well, you heard her.
What devotion.
Anyway, the point is, his
mistake wasn't a fatal one.
Just take the win, OK?
[scoffs] Whatever.
I just don't want anyone
getting in my way.
[MEILI] Do you two
want to stand here
and keep fighting forever?
Even I can't deal with
watching this much longer.
[sighs] You're right.
What we need to do right
now is come up with a plan.
Before Julius
completely recovers,
we need to find out a way
to pass the second exam
that works for all of us.
There was a reason
the examiner
acknowledged Ms. Emelia.
It was because
she got information
out of him while fulfilling
his terms in the process.
That said, the conditions
for passing this exam
are rather fickle.
Yeah, it's nasty
in a totally different way
than the third-floor exam, huh?
[SHAULA] Ain't nothing
wrong with that.
Yeah, no need to rush.
Just take it slow.
Chillax.
Going slow
isn't really an option.
My master and all his
friends are welcome here.
And they can stay
as long as they want.
[grunts]
Hey, in case you forgot,
I waited hundreds of years
for you to finally come back.
Uh, yeah, but--
So I think you can spend
a teensy bit of extra time
around here and pass the exams
the legit way, you know?
And in the meantime,
I will watch over you,
whether it takes
days, years, or centuries.
Just make sure you have
a little fun with me
here before leaving again.
Shaula.
[growling]
Uh.
[whimsical music]
[laughs] This looks good.
These past two days,
you must have been
pretty anxious while I
was out of commission, huh?
So there's no need to hesitate.
You can hang all over me
to your heart's content.
Now, don't be ridiculous.
It isn't like that.
My only purpose
for physical contact
is to collect extra mana
to make up for the time
you spent sleeping, I suppose.
I get that.
But then why did you also
hold my hand while I was asleep
and you couldn't even
collect any mana?
Uh, that had nothing
to do with mana.
It was simply necessary
to keep Betty's heart filled,
and it's unrelated to this.
Ah, there's no need
to worry about me, Beako.
Go right ahead and fatten
yourself up on my mana, OK?
It doesn't matter how
much mana I'm absorbing.
It's not going to make me get
fat or anything, I suppose.
All right, that's
enough, you two.
Now let's dig in.
Today, Mom and I prepared
the meal together.
We'll have to make sure
to take some to Julius later.
[munching]
I'm not surprised.
In fact, I kind of
expected as much.
You have the worst table
manners I've seen in my life.
Has it been that long
since you've had any food?
Nah, it's just this
stuff is too hecka tasty.
What did you
usually eat before?
[SHAULA]
Mabeasts and stuff.
You mean like those
giant worms in the desert?
And stuff like bears
and horses too sometimes.
I never thought I was
the type to be too particular
about food, to be honest.
But if it can be made
to taste this good,
then I might become
the half witch's apprentice.
You'd want to become
my apprentice?
To cook?
I want to get super-duper
good at cooking.
Then when I win master's
heart through his stomach,
I won't let you sleep tonight.
Yeah!
Shame's not in her vocabulary.
[BETTY] Subaru, Betty will
be staying in the carriage
along with Emelia and Rom.
Sure, that sounds good.
But don't stay up all night.
It'll hinder
your growth, and then
you'll end up being
a shrimp forever.
[gasps] You'd be adorable.
All right, stay up all
night, then, Beako.
[sighs] Well, not to worry.
Betty will never get any bigger
than this anyway, I suppose.
No matter what, I will remain
this cute always and forever.
So I can go to sleep
early, I suppose.
OK, Mili, take care of her.
Mm.
Good night then.
And you'd better try not
to stay up too late yourself.
[soft music]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
Subaru, you came back.
Hey, you get a chance to eat?
Yes.
It was lovely.
Here to watch over Ms. Rem?
[sighs] Yeah,
that was the plan.
Do you want to
take over tonight?
No.
You were unconscious for two
days until this morning.
I'm sure she has also been
longing for night to come.
Well, if you want
to let me do it,
then I'm not going to waste
time arguing with you.
But you sure it's OK?
The truth is
that I would prefer
to stay by Ms. Anastasia's
side until she wakes.
But then when
she does awaken,
I am unsure
of what I should say to her.
My hesitation holds me back.
It should be simple.
I've been worried
about you, and I'm
so glad you're finally awake.
Don't you think?
The question is what
you should say after that.
You have such a free
spirited way of thinking.
I quite envy you for that.
Perhaps I'll leave
it to you tonight.
I will return
to the carriage to rest.
Today has been a bit
exhausting, after all.
Julius! Actually, I think
you should stay here and wait
for Ms. Anastasia to wake up.
I'll come wake you up
once I've finished
what I need to do.
♪ ♪
Rem longed
for the night to come, huh?
That's what Julius said.
But...
[murmurs]
[growls]
Oh, crap.
I fell asleep.
[growls]
♪ ♪
Uh, Foxidna?
[eerie music]
[gasps]
Why is there
a bird inside the tower?
♪ ♪
[fluttering]
[panting]
♪ ♪
It vanished?
What?
That can't be.
♪ ♪
Feather.
Is there something
hidden in the wall?
[gulps]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
Foxidna.
- Huh?
Natsuki?
This sure is the perfect view
for taking
a moonlit stroll, isn't it?
Sure is.
It's just a shame you can't
see much at the moment.
That beautiful
view beyond here is
covered up in total darkness.
Sure, it's a little different
at night, but I'm still a fan.
It's like an ocean.
And also, above all else,
the air is so clear
and cool out here,
the stars seem
to shine even brighter.
Romantic, isn't it?
Well, I can't deny how
beautiful the stars are.
So what's your excuse
for this situation?
[FOXIDNA]
Excuse me?
For slipping out of your room
in the middle of the night
without a word
taking a secret passage
in the wall
nobody else knows
about, and coming
outside on the balcony
to play with a bunch
of birds in the night breeze.
It's way too suspicious.
I think you might
be exaggerating a bit
about the secret passage.
I mean, you managed
to find it, didn't you?
That was only because one of
the birds kind of led me here.
Well, that's the same
thing that happened to me.
I was just taking
an aimless midnight
stroll around the tower.
And then I saw a bird
flying in the hall.
I was so curious, I followed it
and ended up here.
Huh.
I wonder, are these
the same birds
we saw flying when
we were trying
to overcome the Sand Time?
You got it, the ones Rom
looked through the eyes of when
using her clairvoyance.
Oh, though I've been curious
about their behavior.
I find it to be
incredibly puzzling.
Right now, you and I
are the only two people
out here in hearing distance.
So why don't we speak frankly?
Not with the me who's
pretending to be Ana,
but instead with the actual me?
That's perfect.
There's something on my mind
I wanted to ask you.
You have a question for me?
Subaru Natsuki, just
who exactly are you?
I'm not sure I follow.
After the big
celebration of your victory
over the White Whale,
and Sloth as well,
Ana went to investigate
you thoroughly.
But she couldn't figure
out your background.
She grumbled about only being
able to learn the bare minimum
despite her best efforts.
The farthest she uncovered
was before the royal selection,
when you had apparently
been involved
in a bit of an incident
within the royal capital.
Again, who exactly are you?
[melancholy music]
Hold on.
Are you seriously afraid of me?
I-- the fact that you would
say such a thing is upsetting.
Tell me, what is the truth
about your connection
to Shaula?
The first time I met her was
after we came here together.
She was a stranger.
During the third-floor exam,
was it just a coincidence
that you figured out the puzzle
so quickly?
It really was.
And what about these birds?
No clue.
I'm a bit afraid to just
take your word for it
without any further proof.
I have a question
to ask as well.
What's going on with
Ms. Anastasia?
There's no change
in her condition,
meaning, just as before,
Ana is still sleeping
deep within this body.
I'm not being optimistic
here or anything.
But the knowledge that I'm
chipping away at her life
steadily weighs on me.
[gasps]
[FOXIDNA] Which is why
I can't waste any more time.
I need to return her body
to her as soon as possible.
In that state, though?
She's barely even surviving.
How could she rule
an entire kingdom?
Ana will never concede.
Nothing could make her give up.
I know that with certainty.
Does Ms. Anastasia want to be
in charge of her own country
that badly?
What if it means
she has to let it go
as soon as she gets
her hands on it?
Yes, even then.
Ana has a reason
she can't give up
on the throne,
whatever it takes.
[wind whistling]
[JULIUS] Care to explain
what you meant by that?
[gasps]
[fluttering]
I need you to explain to me
what you meant by that.
[sighs]
I'm sorry, Julius.
But it's not as if
I was trying to leave
you in the dark or anything.
I was just chatting
with Natsuki
about what we're
all going to have
to think about
when we get back home
after finishing up
this mission.
So, forgive me?
You're not Ms. Anastasia.
You're someone else.
I want you to tell
me everything.
Know this.
You will not
fool me any longer.
Julius, wait.
Hold on!
- Subaru
I'll hear from you too.
The full and complete
truth is all I will accept.
When did you start listening?
From around
when Ms. Anastasia's body
was mentioned.
Oh.
[sighs] I am an artificial
spirit who's been with Ana
for many years already.
My name is Echidna.
Ever since the battle against
the witch cult in Priestella,
Ana's consciousness
has been slumbering deep
within this body.
Meaning she's not
the one making her body
move and speak at the moment.
I've been pretending
to be Ana, and it's
been that way for a while.
[JULIUS] And why did
you choose to only share
this knowledge with Subaru?
[ECHIDNA] That was because he
managed to figure out
that I was a fake on his own.
I had to tell him.
He barely knows her.
How's an outsider able
to notice the difference,
while the man who calls
himself her first knight
failed to recognize
such an important thing?
Just hang on.
Listen!
The only reason
I figured it out
was because, well, it
was only a coincidence.
OK?
Recognizing such coincidences
and turning them
into something definite
is a first knight's duty.
What is a first knight anyway?
If that's what it means,
who needs a stupid--
Do not suggest
I throw it away.
I can't.
Right now, I--
I am terrified by the thought
of letting even
one thing slip away.
Back to the subject.
Echidna, tell me what
your objective is here.
I only wish to return
this body to Ana.
Which means the situation
that you're currently in
is not what you desired.
And you have yet
to discover a way to return
Ms. Anastasia's body to her.
Know that if my death would
allow Ana to live longer...
then I would not hesitate
to accept that outcome.
Help me understand.
Why would you sacrifice
so much for her sake?
It's simply because I love Ana.
Ever since this little
one was very young,
I've been by her side,
supporting her.
So abandoning her
is not an option.
I want her to be happy.
And that is my reason.
♪ ♪
I'm glad you decided to make
such a rational decision.
Ana would certainly be quite
happy with your choice as well.
[metal scraping]
One more thing.
If you keep using
Ms. Anastasia's Od this way
to continually manifest,
then that would also mean,
the more you push
yourself, the more
strain you put on her body.
Yes, you're right.
You perceive that correctly.
If that's true,
on the second floor,
why did you act so recklessly?
Oh.
[JULIUS]
Based on what I saw,
the strain that was
put on her body
while you cast
spell after spell
could not have been trivial.
So what was the purpose?
For that, I apologize.
That was my mistake
and a miscalculation.
But it was a decision made
from a strategic point of view.
Strategic in what way?
[ECHIDNA]
At the time, I didn't yet know
whether that examiner
was out for blood or not.
One wrong action,
and we might have lost you,
one of our strongest assets.
I wanted to avoid that.
And for Ana's sake also.
Understood.
- [gulps]
But please refrain
from acting rashly,
if only
for Ms. Anastasia's sake.
Understood.
What?
That was enough
to convince you?
Yes, it was indeed.
Apologies for involving you in
this strange misunderstanding.
However, this problem shall
remain strictly our own.
It is nothing you need
to concern yourself over.
You can't decide
what I worry about.
I'll make my own judgments.
So you're allowed to decide,
but I don't get to choose
how I handle my own problems?
Just as you didn't tell me
the truth about Ms. Anastasia
and Echidna?
Uh.
Forgive me.
I went too far.
But it is true.
♪ ♪
There is no reason
to stay out here any longer.
Let us go inside.
We shall talk to Ms. Emelia
and the others tomorrow.
We must inform them
of Ms. Anastasia's condition,
as well as Echidna's presence.
Very well.
I too shall steel my resolve.
♪ ♪
Julius.
Don't you have
something you want
to say to me before leaving?
Yes, I do.
I understand.
I understand what
you were thinking
and why you figured
hiding the truth from me
was the best course of action.
You meant no harm in doing so.
It was purely out
of concern and sympathy.
If our positions were reversed,
perhaps I would have refrained
from telling you as well.
However, even still...
I did not want either
Ms. Anastasia or you
to think that I was not worthy
of holding
my title as a knight.
[footsteps echoing]
Barusu.
Hey, Rom.
What are you doing
walking around so late?
Pervert.
- Oh, come on.
Don't try to end the
conversation before it starts.
Hold on, you didn't go upstairs
all by yourself, did you?
Not successfully,
though an attempt was made.
I turned back part way.
Uh.
What were you
doing out and about?
You have an awfully
dejected look on your face.
Did you fight with that
knight Julius or something?
Huh?
Am I that much
of an open book at this point?
That's part of it.
It's also that I am
simply too intelligent.
Well?
- [gulps]
Oh, it's nothing.
Well, no, it wasn't nothing.
But I think I'll be able
to tell you tomorrow.
You sure can talk a lot
without saying a thing.
That's my cue to head
back to the carriage.
Right.
Good night, big sister.
I am not your big
sister, Barusu.
Never call me that again.
[sighs]
Well, I guess
the green room's not an option.
[sighs] So what
should I do instead?
I guess if I can't
sleep anywhere,
I'll try to think of a way
to deal with Reid.
Hmm?
That's it.
If this works, then--
[footsteps echoing]
[EMELIA]
Subaru!
Hey, Subaru!
Are you all right?
Huh?
[exclaims]
[pants] Huh?
Oh, what a relief.
I was really worried about you.
[BETTY] Emelia, you need
to be firmer with him,
or he won't feel bad
about what he's done.
You're right.
Like Beatrice said,
you've been naughty.
She panicked when we
couldn't find you anywhere.
She almost started crying.
We did find you on the ground.
You don't need
to share every little detail
about that with him, I suppose.
[purrs]
[SUBARU] A silver-haired
beauty and a little girl
with ringlets.
A giant lizard and a huge room
covered in living plants.
Hold on.
So does this mean...
Subaru?
I've been summoned across
the universe to another world!
[theme music]
♪ ♪